

# **Babatunde Abioye**

💡 Ibadan, Nigeria 📞 +2347036463485

bmabioye@gmail.com

# Personal Information

WEBSITES. PORTFOLIOS, **PROFILES**  https://www.linkedin.com/in/bmabioye

https://github.com/bmabioye

https://bmabioye.me

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

A Google IT Support Specialist, technology enthusiast, an experienced IT professional with more than 7 years of work in various IT-inclined settings helping small businesses improve productivity. A proactive, servant leader that maximizes the efforts of others toward common goals-a process and detail-oriented individual seeking to advance IT career as an expat.

#### **SKILLS**

Customer Service & Support

Operating Systems (Windows, Linux, MacOS)

Computer networking [LAN, WLAN, VLAN]

Programming languages [HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Python] Virtualization

Remote Connections & Cloud Computing

Troubleshooting & Repair

Systems Administration/Configuration

Implementing/managing directory services | Data management

ERP & POS Systems Configuration | CCTV & Intercom Telephony

IT security | Cryptology/encryption | IT Systems/Infrastructure

# **NATIONALITY DATE OF BIRTH GENDER**

Nigeria

27-07-1986

Male

#### **DESIRED POSITION**

# IT SUPPORT SPECIALIST / HELPDESK

### Work Experience

**DATES** 

**POSITION RESPONSIBILITIES**  June 2015 - present

#### **Business Management Specialist** [Self-Employ]

- Proffer business solutions for small and medium enterprises.
- Efficiently and friendly support customers in their business needs
- Demonstrated respect, friendliness and willingness to help regularly.

#### **EMPLOYER / ADDRESS BUSINESS**

Lovelamp Systems & Consulting Firm / Ibadan – Nigeria Information Technology | Web Solution | Training

## **DATES POSITION RESPONSIBILITIES**

August 2018 - March 2021

#### **ICT Solution Consultant.** [Contract]

- Seamlessly oversaw, managed and coordinated the ICT department
- Procured, managed, and administered computers & other IT infrastructures
- Network monitoring and configuration including routers, VPNs, RDP, etc
- Implement WebApp and integrate solutions into business operations
- Maintained and repaired computers, other IT equipment and tools to sustained uninterrupted operation.

#### **EMPLOYER / ADDRESS TYPE OF BUSINESS**

Country Kitchen Ventures / Ibadan – Nigeria Hospitality | Restaurant | Retail



**POSITION** 

**RESPONSIBILITIES** 

August 2017 - March 2020

#### **System Administrator** [Contract]

- Setup local and live web-server for WebApp deployment
- Managed and configured remote connection
- Configured Google virtual machines
- -Setup, deployed digital Ocean droplets

**EMPLOYER / ADDRESS TYPE OF BUSINESS** 

XPL Developers / Ibadan – Nigeria Blockchain | Web Development | ICT

**DATES** 

August 2013 - March 2015 [Full-time]

## **POSITION**

#### **Customer Care Representative / Supervisor**

- **RESPONSIBILITIES**
- Actively listened to customers' requests, confirming full understanding before addressing concerns
- Prepare a variety of different written communications, reports and documents to ensure smooth operations
- Carried out day-to-day duties accurately and efficiently

**EMPLOYER / ADDRESS TYPE OF BUSINESS**  MTN Nigeria Trade Partner / Oshogbo – Nigeria Mobile Operation | Customer Service | Retail | Telecoms

**Education and Training** 

2021

**QUALIFICATION AWARDED PRINCIPAL STUDIES** 

### **Google IT Support**

IT Security | Operating Systems | Computer Networking System Administration and Infrastructure Services Technical Support Fundamentals

**INSTITUTION** 

Coursera / Google

**DATES QUALIFICATION AWARDED PRINCIPAL STUDIES**  2013

# **Customer Care Training**

Customer Service | Mobile Devices Troubleshooting Mobile Device Configuration | Help Desk | Retail

**INSTITUTION** 

MTN Service Centre, Ibadan

**DATES QUALIFICATION AWARDED PRINCIPAL STUDIES** 

2011

**Bachelor of Technology | Mathematics & Computer Science** Computer Architecture, Algorithm, Software Design, AI, DBMS

**INSTITUTION** 

Federal University of Technology, Minna - Nigeria

Skills and Competences **LANGUAGE SPOKEN** OTHER LANGUAGE(S)

English [Fluent]

Yoruba [Native], Arabic[Hesitant], Mandarin[Beginner]

Certifications **SOCIAL SKILLS AND COMPETENCES** 

Comptia A+ Certification Google IT Support Certificate

Accomplishments

2018

**DATE PROJECT USE CASE** 

Use Microsoft Excel to build a loan management application Community Effort